<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacques Peeters&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jacques Peeters&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaggle instacart (top2%) feature engineering and solution overview</title>
      <link>/2017/08/28/kaggle-instacart-solution-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/28/kaggle-instacart-solution-overview/</guid>
      <description>Intro This blog post aims at showing what kind of feature engineering can be achieved in order to improve machine learning models.
I entered Kaggle’s instacart-market-basket-analysis challenge with goals such as :
 finish top5% of a Kaggle competition keep learning Python (i come from R)  I ended up 52nd (top2%) ouf of 2623 data scientists, which i’m pretty happy with afterwards eventhough i was bitter during the last week because i lost some competitive edges i had due to the release of this and this public posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hint at a better parallelization of groupby in Pandas</title>
      <link>/2017/08/21/parallel-pandas-groupby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/21/parallel-pandas-groupby/</guid>
      <description>Intro Parallelizing large amount of groups might requiere a lot of time without parallization. However directly parallize groups when the number of groups is very large and the function applied to each of them is rather fast, might lead to worse result than no parallezation.
Parallelizing every group creates a chunk of data for each group. Each chunk needs to be transfered to cores in order to be processed. Transfering chunk of data costs time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hellow world, i&amp;rsquo;m jacques peeters, a data scientist consultant and a Kaggler expert.
Python and R are my favorite tools. I compete on Kaggle and DataScience.net in order to sharpen my machine learning skills. I regularly attend &amp;ldquo;Paris Machine Learning&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;French Data&amp;rdquo; meetups.
My goal is to link the academic world to business&amp;rsquo; opportunities.
Find out more about me by visiting my LinkedIn/Github account!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>